暂告安全 （三区台版官方字幕）
（纽约布鲁克林市 一小时前）
BROOKLYN, NY One hour earlier
在说谎
You're lying to me.
我没有 我不知道你在说什么
l'm not. l don't know what you're talking about.
也不知道你要什么
l don't know what you want from me.
我真的不知道
l swear l don't .
我有三个小孩
l have three children.
当父亲得先学会一件事
The first thing you have to learn as a father,
就是分辨孩子是否在骗人
is to know when your children are lying to you.
在骗我
You're lying to me.
要是敢再骗我
And if you don't stop,
我会用你们中国人的酷刑
l'm going to use one of those tortures your people are so famous for...
折磨到说实话为止!
...on your little body, until you tell me what l want to know!
我再说一次
For the last time...
把号码说出来!
Give me the numbers!
（中国南京市 一年前）
NANJlNG, CHlNA One year earlier
204的35倍是另外一种算法 加起来是350
如果用另外一种算法
Try it the other way,
加起来是365
it adds up to three hundred and sixty five...
只有一个算法是对的
Only one answer is correct.
苏先生，我没有不尊重你的意思
l mean no disrespect, Mr. Sook,
但是你的算法是错的
...but your calculations are wrong.
梅…
Mei...
我们帮转去另一个学校
we're going to move you to a different school.
但是我的朋友都在这儿
But all my friends are here, and my mother...
而且我的妈妈… 梅，太聪明 是个天才
Mei. you are so smart, a genius.
该上一个特殊的学校
You have to go to an appropriate school...
可以找新朋友的
You'll make new friends.
别难过，梅 我们永远都是的朋友
Don't ‘ be sad Mei, we'll always be your friends.
听说北京的小孩人都很好的
l hear the kids in Beijing are cool,
在那会过得很开心的
you'll have a good time there.
我根本就不喜欢数字
But l don't even like numbers.
我喜欢我现在的朋友
l like my friends here.
我不想要交新的朋友
l don't want new friends.
我不喜欢数学
l don't like math.
来做数学
Of course you do...
我们给写信 我们每个星期
都给往北京写封信
don't worry, we'll send you a letter every week.
- 你发誓？ - 当然
You promise? Of course.
想让我们失去… 一个有名的朋友吗？
Think we want to miss out on having a famous friend
对了，梅
我们永远都是的… 梅…
lt's gonna be great, Mei...
（纽泽西梅多兰市）
THE MEADOWLANDS, NJ
你还敢来？不准你来!
How dare you come here?
妈!够了!住手!
You have no right! Mom, mom! Enough! Stop!
你没权利来这里
You have no right to be here.
你应该去坐牢! 你应该去坐牢!
You should be in jail.
给我滚! 你给我滚!
You get out of here!
- 对不起 - 我要杀了你…
- l'm sorry. - l'll kill you.
人渣!
Piece of garbage!
你不该让他上场打的!
He should never have been in there with me!
别这样!你疯了吗？
Come on! What, are you crazy man?
别碰我!
Get off!
我很讨厌你，路克
l never liked you, Luke.
你比九成的对手都强
You're a better fighter than ninety percent of the guys you go into the cage with.
但你老让人当沙包打
But you just let 'em pound on you like you're a side of beef.
所有人都赢过你
You already lost to every chump in the circuit.
但你偏偏要在昨晚找麻烦
But last night, of all nights!
你早该在第二局被击倒的
You're supposed to go down in the second, you son of a bitch!
你他妈的混蛋! 一拳，我只打了他一拳!
Once. l hit him once!
你是从育幼院找来的人吗？
Where'd you find him, in the fucking playground?
YouTube上找来的，混球!
YouTube, you asshole!
这家伙人气超高 结果被你打成昏迷
The kid is an lnternet sensation, until you put him in a coma.
不过我才懒得鸟他!
Which frankly, l do not give a shit about!
但你害我赔了一百万!
But you cost me a million dollars!
多切斯基赔的更惨
Which is nothing compared to what you cost Docheski.
想起他了吗？
Yeah, you recognize the name?
他砸大钱赌你输!
He was betting on you, big time to take the dive!
现在连我都遭殃了
And he's going to take it out on me, too.
因为比赛是我安排的
Because he knows l'm the schmuck who set this whole thing up.
除非我拿你的人头做人情
Unless, l deliver your head with a down payment.
俄罗斯人可不好惹
You know how the Russians are.
阿梅…
这个是我侄女，白羽
This is my niece, Bai Yu.
认识吧？
Recognize her?
她在我同样的一班里
She's in my class at school.
她说的脑筋… 很像计算机
She says you mind is like a computer.
我跟的老师讲过了 他也这样说
We spoke to your teacher and he said the same thing.
知道了吧
That's why you're here.
很可爱啊
Lovely girl.
计算机很讨厌 太容易留下痕迹
Computers are so annoying, they leave trails that are easy to follow.
他们还说…
走开…
学过的东西是不会忘的 是不是啊？
They say what you learn you never forget. ls that so?
那我到的家
Then we will go to your home and kill your mother
把妈妈杀掉好不好啊？
for making such a stupid girl.
很好… 看来他们说对了
So they are telling the truth.
苏先生告诉我
Mr. Sook also said your father ran away when you were very little,
小的时候爸爸已经走掉了
left your mother,
的妈妈正在生病
And you mother is very ill.
很快就变成一个人 喜欢孤独吗？
Soon you will be all alone. So you want to be all alone?
放心 我们会好好照顾的妈妈
Then we will take good care of your mother.
他姓张，是的新爸爸
This is Chang, your new father.
他会带飘洋过海
He will take you far over the ocean,
那边的人很喜欢找我们麻烦
where our enemies like to make trouble for us.
所以我要帮我们算一算
Once you are there... You will count for us.
这是莱特家，请留言
You've got the Wright number, to leave the right message.
收到马上打给我，安妮
Call me when you get this Annie.
马上出门
Leave right away.
如果在外面就别回家
lf you're out, don't go home.
的处境很危险 快回电
lf l'm scaring you, that's good. Call me.
安妮？
Annie?
他租的片还不错
He has some nice videos.
投降了吗？
That's it?
听说你很能打
l heard you were some kind of tough guy.
不露两招吗？
No fighting?
别像条死狗一样赖在地上
You're just going to sit on the floor like a dog who wants to die.
抱歉，我们动粗了
Sorry it had to be so messy.
小孩子还不懂事
The boy is still learning.
我不是医生 但看得出来她怀孕了
And l'm not a doctor, but l think she was eating for two.
我们很像曼森家族吧？
We're like the Charlie Manson family. No?
我爸原本想派别人来 不过我想打响名号
My father was going to send someone else, but l'm making my bones.
你惹毛了会让你残废的人
You make your bones by killing someone who could hurt you back.
你在说谁？
And who would that be?
你吗？ 我无所谓 你刚杀了你老婆
You? Well, why not? You just killed you wife.
我没有杀他，是你杀的
l didn't kill her. You did.
你想让我残废吗？
But, you want to hurt me?
很好，我倒想见识一下
Good. l'd like to see you try.
快把帐算一算
Get it over with.
你害我爸赔钱 让我的家族没面子
Over? You cost my father money. Made my family look bad.
所以我们要杀鸡儆猴
Now, we're going to make an extra special example out of you.
我们看过你的档案 没什么特别的
So, we looked into your records. Not much to find.
当过公务员、收垃圾的
Worked for City, Garbage collections, Sanitation.
还有清洁工 福利不错，但没啥出息
Good benefits, but no glamor.
父母双殁
Father and mother, dead.
没有兄弟姊妹
No brothers or sisters.
真是遗憾啊
Which is too bad,
因为我很想杀光他们
because l would like to take them from you too.
不过我们知道你很爱你老婆
But you loved your wife. We know that.
这样好了 我们放你一马
So, here's the deal. You are free to go.
不过我们偶尔会来找你
But we will have eyes on you.
只要你一不注意我们就会出现
Not always. But when you least expect it, we'll be there.
你结交的任何人
Anyone you try to make friends with, or even talk to...
包括说过话的人 除了卖东西的店家
...other than ordering a hot dog or something,
全部都会死
will die.
就像你老婆一样 这都是你害的
Like your wife. Because of you.
你也可以结束这一切
Of course you can always end it.
找个桥往下跳 跳轨自杀也不错
Jump off a bridge, throw yourself in front of a train.
如果你信上帝那一套
Damn your eternal soul to Hell.
自杀是会下地狱的
lf you believe in that kind of bull shit.
但我可不信的 所以换作我就会去自杀
Personally l don't , so l'd go for it if l were you.
还好我不是你，感谢上帝
But, l am not you. Thank God.
你自己选吧
So do what you want.
你要是明天还赖在这里 我们就干掉包租婆
lf you're still here tomorrow, we're going to kill the land lady.
她叫啥来着？ 托柏洛斯基之类的
What was her name? Tobolovski, or something.
托柏洛斯基太太
Mrs. Tobolovski.
人还不错
Nice lady.
快打扫吧，收垃圾的
Clean up the mess, Garbage man.
好了，她是你女儿 所以是美国公民
Alright, she's your daughter, and she's an American citizen.
我不会过问她的事
l ain't going to ask what the deal is with her.
那是你的私事
That is your business.
但我得跟你说 动用关系很辛苦
But l'm going to tell you, pulling strings is hard work.
而辛苦就要有代价
And hard work don't come free.
开个价吧，沃夫队长
Your price, Captain Wolf?
中国城管区涨了二十趴
Chinatown Precinct take goes up twenty percent.
布隆克斯管区要先缴一万二
Bronx, hundred twenty first,
布鲁克林管区全面涨十趴
Brooklyn Divisions each go up by ten percent.
是每个月来算
Monthly.
帮小孩办个护照也太贵了吧
That's a steep price for a passport and some papers for a little girl.
现在越来越难混了
Things are tough all over.
中国城可以涨十趴
Chinatown gets up ten percent.
其它两区不能涨
Bronx and Brooklyn will settle for the current rate.
我们答应不会像疯狗咬人一样
And the fact that we won't start shooting cops and their families in the streets...
见条子就杀
...like dogs at the first sign of pressure.
现在越来越难混了
Things are tough all over.
老兄，我见过你
Hey man, l know you.
我在纽泽西看过你比赛
l saw your fight in Jersey, it was really good.
你很厉害，把对手打昏了
You knocked that guy out.
不是我 真的超诺
No. That was some good shit, man.
打得很精彩
Great fight.
刘伟的店 这个礼拜是两万六千
Wei Lu's store, twenty six thousand this week.
上个礼拜是26
Twenty six last week.
何金每个礼拜是正好一万五千
Hojin is even at fifteen thousand a week.
他在75柏瑞斯的店
His store on Bowery St showed a profit for May.
（纽约中国城 一年后）
五月在赔钱
但七八月就赚回来了
CHlNATOWN, NY One year later His store on Bowery St showed a profit for May. CHlNATOWN, NY One year later
劭成上个礼拜是42
CHlNATOWN, NY One year later Cheng Sao, forty two last week, forty two point five this week...
这个礼拜42.5
Cheng Sao, forty two last week, forty two point five this week...
每个月盈利成长百分之7
His shop is showing a seven percent increase in earnings every month.
马街的总共盈利…
ln total Mott Street's earnings are up seventy two thousand,
是上升了7万2535
five hundred and thirty five dollars.
我们从梁先生那里… 拿了百分之5
Our other stores are all up five percent...
他们每个礼拜盈利六千到八千
weekly profits should be between six thousand and eight thousand each.
那赌场呢？
And the Casino?
上个礼拜是八十万
Eight hundred thousand last week.
这个礼拜也是八十万
This week also eight hundred thousand.
刚好八十万整？
Exactly eight hundred thousand.
差不多八十万
lt's almost eight hundred.
我不是要大概的数字
l'm not asking you if it's almost eight hundred.
我要实际数字
l want the exact number.
78万5370元
Seven hundred eighty five thousand three hundred and seventy dollars.
上个礼拜呢？
And the week before?
钱少了
lt's losing money.
找死
停!
拜托不要打了
今晚你们会有个新的厂商工头
You'll have a new floor boss tonight.
如果钱又少了 那就不知道谁会倒霉
lf the tally comes up short again, he won't be the only one who suffers.
怎么了？
What?
为什么？
Why?
因为他危害到生意 而生意是很重要的
Because he was hurting business, and business is a serious matter.
我懂生意
l understand business.
既然你要杀他，干嘛还要打他？
But why beat him if you're going to kill him anyway.
看来还是不懂这个生意
lf you're asking me that, it means you still don't understand business.
不说了，吃的饭
Now be quiet and eat.
The chicken's gone, l killed them. My grandmother used to sing.
去你的!我操!
Oh fuck you! Fuck you!
No, no. Okay, you're wet. Pink.
Oh nothing, nothing.
你不能进来
You can't come in the shelter.
我只想吃点东西
l'm just trying to get something to eat, man!
你不准进来 先穿的象样点才说
You ain't going to eat in here. You got to get a shirt first. Just go back, man.
动作快，五分钟后熄灯
Wrap it up. Lights out in five.
动作快
Wrap it up.
配合一下
Come on guys.
鞋子不赖
Nice kicks.
你最好别偷走它
They better be here in the morning...
否则我让你用耳朵穿鞋
...or you'll be wearing them on your ears.
因为我会啃了你的脚
Because l'll chew your feet off at the God damn ankles.
我真的需要双新鞋
l could really use some new shoes, man.
我什么都愿意做
l'll do what ever you want, you know?
我可以让你舒服一下
Whatever gets you through the night.
我很难受…
l just l can't take...
闭嘴…
Shut up, shut up.
你拿去吧 我还有别双鞋
Shut up and take 'em. l've still got my old ones.
去找医生看一下
Go get those feet looked at.
都长坏疽了
Gangrene is setting in.
我会的
l will.
谢谢你
Thank you, man.
上帝爱你，兄弟
Jesus loves you, brother.
上帝爱你
Jesus loves you.
熄灯了 早上七点准时起床
Lights out. Wake up call is seven AM. Lights out.
熄灯了
Lights out.
梅，我有个坏消息要告诉
Mei, l have sad news.
我听他们说…
l heard them talking.
妈死了
Your mother is gone.
她两周前在医院走的
She died two weeks ago in the hospital.
他们想瞒着
They weren't going to tell you.
我想通知 让祷告让她上天堂
But l'm telling you, so that you can pray for her soul to find its way to heaven.
别跟他们提起 如果知道是我讲的…
Please don't say anything. lf they found out l told you.
我不会讲的，谢谢
l won't say anything. Thank you.
全部起床 收容所九点要净空
Everybody up. Shelter needs to be cleared by nine AM.
记得三点半前先登记 请把随身物品带走
Remember, reservations for tonight must be made before by three thirty.
能告诉我们发生什么事吗？
So you want to tell us what happened?
有人欣赏他的鞋
Someone liked his shoes.
真幽默，你觉得好笑吗？
Funny guy. You think this is a joke?
你们这些警卫真无能
You know, you guys are a Hell of a crack Security Squad.
你昨晚睡他旁边 你应该救他才对
You were right here. You could have said something.
我看你是喝挂了吧？
But you were too busy sleeping off this contraband. Right?
你再有胆来这里
Come into this shelter again,
我就把你这垃圾扔出去
and l will run your raggedy ass back out into the street.
阿梅啊 到房间去 记住这些数字好不好？
l want you to take this to your room and l want you to memorize it. Then...
我已经记住了
l've memorized it.
这些数字很重要
This is an extremely important number.
为了妈，要小心一点 知道吗？
For your mother's sake, answer me carefully.
真的记住了？
Are you sure you have memorized it?
我可以给你重复一遍 但是又长又无聊
l can repeat it for you, but it would be long and boring.
你看 还不到一年 她已经像老美了
Look at that. here hardly for a year, and already she has American attitude.
如果她说她可以背住密码
lf she says she remembers it,
她就能背住密码
she remembers it.
我保证
l can vouch for that.
好啦…
我们要交给一个很重要的工作
Then l have a very important job for you.
走路小心一点!
Hey! Watch where you're going, man!
当心我揍你!
You could get your ass kicked for that. Okay? Huh?
四块五毛五
Four fifty five.
如果没钱就请离开
lf you got no money, you got to get out of line.
我有钱
l got money.
他根本没钱
He doesn't have any money. Look at him.
你看他的样子 先生，我说过了 如果没钱就请离开
Mister, l told you, if you don't have money you have to leave. Okay?
不要挡路，大家都在等
You have to get out of line. People are waiting.
帮个忙，请你离开
Come on buddy, you have to go.
他在捣乱吗？
ls this guy giving you trouble?
他疯了，长官 请把他赶出去
He's crazy officer, get him out of here.
来，咱们离开吧
Alright come on, let us go.
就是你，走吧 快离开这家店!
Hey you! Come on, lets go! Out, on the street!
走吧，风趣男 想当小丑就去马戏团
Let us go funny boy. You want to be a clown, go join the circus, not in my Precinct.
别在这闹事，听到没有？ 我不想再看到你
You hear me? l don't want to see you around here. Hey.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
猜我抓到谁了？
Look at what the cat dragged in.
真不敢相信
Unbelievable.
你看看他
Look at him.
看看他？
Look at him?
不如闻闻吧
How about the smell?
我联络其它人
l'll call the boys.
阿梅，这是的指令
Mei, these are your instructions:
张会带去见一个人 那个人会给一组新的数字
Chang will take you to meet a man who has a second number...
记住那组数字
You will memorize it.
然后呢… 张会带去一个地方
Then you'll be taken to another location,
会得到最后的指令
where your final instructions will be given to you.
想念我们吗？
You miss us partner?
欢迎你归队
Welcome back to the force.
梅，学得很快
You're learning fast.
如果干得好
lf you do this job well,
会跟着韩叔前途无量
you have a bright future in business with Uncle Han.
对不起，不能让落入他们手中
l'm sorry. l can't let them have you.
今天过得好吗，路克？
How's your day been, Luke?
早上不太顺 不过渐入佳境啦
Started lousy. But it's looking up.
路克莱特
Luke Wright, the Big Apple's hardest cop.
曾是纽约最难缠的条子 你很能打
Once upon a time. Always could take a shot.
但你知道你的专长是啥吗？
But you know what your real talent is? You're a uniter.
当招集人 有谁想得到…
l mean, who'd have thought that us and the Ruskies
我们和老俄这么有默契
would ever be on the same page about anything?
不是我
Not me.
很高兴见到你
Nice to see you, rat.
我老早就看你不顺眼了!
l've been wanting to do this ever since the day you opened your big fucking mouth!
多切斯基的事我们听说了 真是大快人心
We heard what Docheski did to you. l mean, l had to laugh.
我们真替安妮惋惜 只能算她倒霉
l mean, we felt bad for Annie and all but them's the breaks.
嫁到这种烂老公
She knew who she was with.
听到你出现的消息
When word come up you were on the street you were back.
我们真是不敢相信
We couldn't believe our fucking ears.
你回来干嘛？
Now, why would you come back?
为何就不能滚远一点？
Why wouldn't you disappear somewhere far away?
例如去月球之类的
Like the Moon.
我想家
l missed home.
你曾是我们的一员 我们曾是伙伴
You were one of us, Luke. We were a team.
就像家人一样 结果你背叛我们
We were family. Then you threw us under the bus.
我们以前是皇帝!
We were Kings, you son of a bitch!
现在沦为一群奴隶!
Now, we are a bunch of god damned serfrs!
冷静点，班诺
Whoa, whoa. Hey, hey, hey, easy Benoit.
你既然敢回来 应该就是活腻了
When you come back, We figured you wanted to die.
有很多方法可以死
You know, we got a pool going on when you're going to end it, and how.
撞公交车、跳火车…
You know. Bus, train...
我赌你被警枪打死
l got my money on suicide by cop.
拿去吧
Come on, take it.
一枪就解脱了
Take a shot. Come on.
安妮正等着你呢
Annie's waiting for you.
问题是…她会想见你吗？
Question is, do you really think she wants to see you again?
其实我真正的专长…
Actually, my real talent
是害人赔钱
is costing other people money.
先提醒你，莱斯基 你会赌输的
You ought to know that, Lasky. You're going to lose that bet.
除非你从背后开抢
Unless you want to shoot me in the back.
反正你也习惯了
lt wouldn't be your first time.
你为何不自我了结？
Why don't you just end it?
你还在等什么？
What are you waiting for,
想害死更多人吗？
more people around you to die?
你到底在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
我再说一次 把号码说出来
For the last time. Give me the numbers.
既勇敢又聪明
You're a very brave girl, and clever.
但知道自己的天分吗？
But do you know how exactly what you can do?
知道该用在什么地方吗？
Where you're going to be and when?
有人告诉你了
Someone told you.
没错 知道是谁吗？
That's right. Can you guess who?
让她进来
Let her in.
的朋友 她告诉母亲的事
A friend. The one who told you who told you about your poor mother.
而诱拐的人却想隐瞒
When the scum who took you from home would not.
她和我们合作愉快
She's working for us with a smile.
梅，我跟他们讲他们想知道的事情
Mei, l tell these men what they want to know,
他们就给我一把一把的钱
and they pay me lots and lots of money.
要是这么做 他们也会帮助的
Do the same and they will help you too.
真是个笨女人
You are a stupid woman.
讲英文
ln English.
不知道生意 给他们要的东西 现在他们要杀了
You gave them what they want, now they're going to kill you.
我叫说英文
l said, speak in English.
听到没？
Well?
她不肯说
She won't tell me anything.
我父亲很有耐性
My father is a patient man.
我没有
l am not.
快说出来，不然杀了
Tell him what he wants to know, or l will kill you.
警察，快开门
NYPD, open the door!
搞什么鬼？ 我们是警察 邻居检举你们太吵
What the Hell? This is the Police. We got a report of a disturbance.
你们可以乖乖听话 我们也能来硬的
Look, you can make this easy, or you can it hard.
快开门，否则我们就冲进去
Open the door, or we come in by force!
听你在放屁!
Bull shit Blue!
你们敢进来老子保证干掉你们!
You come in here, you go out feet first. l swear on my mother!
人都在里面，队长
Yeah, they're in there Captain.
我不知道你的目的
l don't know what the Hell you're looking for
但他们不肯配合
but they are not cooperating.
我们得在场面失控前冲进去
You'd better get down here before things go to Hell.
不行…这是大事件
Negative, negative, this is big.
我要回警局掌控情势
l'm going back to the station to monitor the city.
待会打给你
l'll get back to you.
我们包围他们了
Alright, we've got them pinned down, you know what l want.
你知道我要什么 我们有过协议
We have a deal.
能抢回女孩就留活口 不能的话就杀了她
Get the girl. Alive if you can, dead if you can't .
派人进去，布鲁克林要涨十趴
We go in, Brooklyn stake goes up by ten percent.
这是新价码
That's the new deal.
等等，我接个插播
Hold on, l got an incoming call.
艾米尔，有何贵干？
Hey, Emile. What's up?
叫你的人走，沃夫
Back your men off, Wolf.
不管老中给你多少 我多出五趴
Whatever the Chinese offer to you, l'll up it by five percent.
把她抓回来!
Get here back here!
阿宽，老俄愿意加七趴
Alright Quan, l have the Russians offering up Brooklyn's stake by seven percent, Bronx is the same.
布隆克斯维持现状 我不知该如何启齿
l don't know what to tell you.
下面的人不介意开战
l talked to my guys, they're willing to go to war over this.
你将与我们为敌 像希特勒一样被围攻
You know, you're going to be stuck between us and the Russians and us like Hitler; fighting on two fronts.
建议你好好考虑一下
So you had better think hard about this one.
两个管区各加十趴 不要拉倒
Ten percent, both precincts; final offer.
嘿，麦克
Hey Mack, both these bastards are willing to pay a stiff price
两帮人都开高价抢那个女孩
for this little Chink girl.
我要她身上的东西
What ever she's got, l want it.
我们该怎么做？
So what is our play?
我让老俄放下戒心
l get the Russians to drop their guard, you go in.
你们冲进去 如果女孩中枪
lf she catches a bullet l want you to take out everyone
就把那群人渣全杀光
last one of those Bolshevik scumbags.
艾米尔，我接受条件
Alright Emile, your offer is good.
我会叫人撤退 因为我比较喜欢你
l'm going to call my guys off, but only because l like you better.
放你个屁 你这贪心的混蛋
Bullshit. You're a greedy bastard, Wolf.
你一看到有好处 就想占尽便宜
You got the scent of something big and now you want it all for yourself.
在你的人进来大开杀戒前 我得先跟你说
But l have to pay something before you send your men in gun blazing.
她不见了
She is gone.
什么叫她不见了？
What do you mean, she is gone?
她逃走了
l mean, she escaped.
外面都是你的人 我不能追出去
And will all your men out there l can't follow.
找到她之前先休战吧
l offer you a truce until we find her.
相信我，如果老中先找到她
Trust me, if the Chinese find her first,
你会后悔一辈子的
that will be a thing you regret as long as you live.
多切斯基
Docheski,
她为何这么重要？
what does she have?
要休战吗，沃夫队长？
Do we have a truce, Captain Wolf?
是个中国女孩，年约十一岁
The girl is Chinese, eleven years old.
会说中文和英文
She speaks Mandarin and English.
照片已经公布了
Her photo is being disseminated.
一定要找到她 找到就带到中央街
You are to find her and bring her straight to Center Street.
动作快 她朝着地铁站去了
Move now, she is headed for subway.
警察跟我们干上了
The police have screwed us.
是吗？
ls that so?
你没有办法？
That's all you have to say?
你这个不动脑筋的笨蛋
You're an idiot.
如果让警察和俄国人… 先找到那个女孩
lf you don't find the girl before the police do...
我就砍了你的人头
your head will be gone in an instant.
我们开打吧
Let's go to war.
对不起，安妮
Sorry, Annie.
俄罗斯人在J街消失了
Lost my lock on the Russian Cell on " J" Street.
看来是进了地铁站
Sounds like they went into the Subway Station,
往曼哈顿走
Manhattan bound.
是你？收垃圾的？
You? The garbage collector?
你资料有误
You got bad information.
我从没收过垃圾
l never collected garbage.
我只清除垃圾
l disposed of it.
别吓到，是他自找的
Don't lose sleep. He had it coming.
没事吧？
Are you all right?
快逃… 赶快跑
Get out, get out. Move.
没事了
lt's okay.
找到人就带到中央街
When found, she is to be brought to Captain Wolf at Center Street.
别怕… 孩子，我们是警察
Whoa, easy. Easy there, Hon. We're the police...
我们会保护
...everything's alright.
叫什么名字？
Hey, what's you name, Hon?
就是她 不确定，中国人长得都一样
This is her. l don't know, they all look alike to me.
你有照片吗？ 有，我找找
You got that picture up? Yeah, let me see.
去他妈的纽约市
Fucking New York City,
几百年不见你们
don't see somebody for years...
同一天却给我遇到两次
...and you bump into them twice in the same day.
我不会伤害的
Hey, hey. l'm not going to hurt you.
到底做了什么事？
What the Hell did you do, kid?
那些追的人是坏蛋
You know, those men who are chasing you are bad.
他们为何要抓？
You want to tell me why they're after you?
听得懂吗？
Do you understand me?
会讲英文吗？
Do you speak English?
什么叫西米亚他们不见了？
What do you mean Chemyakin and the others disappeared? Someone else has taken her.
她被别人带走了
No, not the police.
他不是条子 有两个条子差点被他干掉
He nearly killed a couple of cops.
也不是中国佬
Not the Chinese, either.
我不知道他是谁
l don't know who the hell he is.
那就干掉他 活捉那个女孩
Then kill him, and take the girl alive.
抓不到就连她也一起干掉
lf you can't , then kill her too.
你走反了 你在逆向行驶!
The other way. Cars go the other way!
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy, man?
抓稳了
Hold on.
这样下去，会有很多人受牵连
This goes on, a lot of innocent people are going to get hurt.
希望那样吗？
You want that?
很好，那就听我的话
Good, then do what l say.
没事吧？
Are you okay?
走吧
Let us go.
我不是五岁小孩
l'm not five years old.
那就动作快点
Then keep up.
抓到人却搞丢了
You had her, and you lost her.
不，队长 我们没搞丢她
No Captain, we didn't lose her.
她是被人劫走的
She was taken by force.
是那群老俄 不是他们干的
The Russians. No, not the Russians.
是路克莱特
Well, it was Luke Wright.
什么？ 沃夫队长 我现在没空，迪克
What? - Captain Wolf. - Not now, Deke.
市长找你，队长
The mayor wants you, Captain.
转到二线来 他不是打电话来
Put him through on two. He is not on the phone.
他叫你去他家，昨天说的
He wants you at the mansion. Yesterday.
麻烦签名
Here you go.
谢谢你，艾凡诺先生
Thank you Mister lvanov.
谢谢
Thank you.
艾凡诺先生？ 这是你的房门卡
Mister lvanov? Here you are Mister lvanov.
房号是1012，在10楼
Room 1012 on the tenth floor.
谢谢
Thank you.
你喜欢住好饭店
You like a nice hotel.
我从没住过好饭店
l never stayed in a nice hotel.
坏蛋不会来这里
No one is going to look for us in one.
她一定在这里
She's in the area,
不过我看不清楚
but there's a lot of interfrerence...
干扰太多了
l can't be more specific.
等一下
Wait...
等一下!
wait!
我找到她了
Got her.
真想冲个澡
Man, would l like a shower.
你应该洗个澡
You could use one.
干脆让老俄抓走算了
l could've just let those Russians grab you on the train.
你为什么要救我？
Why did you save me?
我没有救
l didn't save you.
是救了我
You saved me.
我只是报恩
l'm paying you back.
我叫路克
My name is Luke.
我叫梅
Mei.
的父母呢？
You have parents, Mei?
我有爸爸
l have a father.
他叫什么名字？
What's his name?
张宽
Chang Quan.
如果是我认识的那个
lf we're talking about the same guy,
我记得他没小孩
he didn't have any kids last time l checked.
就算有也不到三岁
Any that he made since wouldn't be a day over three years old.
我是领养的
l'm adopted.
在中国领养的吗？
Did he bring you over from back home?
他不是当父亲的料
Chang isn't the fatherly type.
为何来这里？
Why are you here, Mei?
记数字
To count.
是那个老鬼找来的 张的老板
You were send over by the old guy, Chang's boss. What's his name?
那个老古董叫啥？
Old school.
他怕计算机会留记录
No computers, no electronic trails.
所以要记数字，对吧？
Just what you have in our head. Right?
认识韩交？
You know Jiao Han?
听说过他
l know of him.
他告诉我一组号码 很长的一组号码
He told me a number, a very long number.
我原本要去另一个地方 拿第二组号码和指令
l was going someplace where l would get another number and instructions.
但俄国人杀了所有人
But the Russians came and shot everyone.
我趁警察来时逃走了
Then the police came and l ran away.
现在你全知道了，满意了吗？
Now you know everything. Happiness for you?
想回韩交那吗？
You want to go back to Han Jiao?
我惹上不少麻烦，是个累赘
l make too much trouble. Bad business.
等我办完事，他就会杀了我
After l do what he asks, he kills me.
省得他烦恼 那是什么号码？
Good business. So, what about this number?
又长又无聊的号码
lt is long boring number.
我可以告诉你
l can tell it to you.
那对我毫无意义
lt wouldn't mean anything to me.
怎么知道是一组号码 而不是单独的号码？
But how do you know it is one number and not a bunch of separate numbers?
你虽然是疯子 但并不笨
You're a crazy man. But not so stupid.
号码有特别的地方吗？
ls there anything interesting to you about these numbers?
有些数字有
Maybe a few of them.
为什么？
Why?
因为前面有三或七
Because they have a three or a seven before them.
所有数字都是随机的
All the numbers are random.
可是有五个数字前面有七
But, five of them have a seven before it.
有八个数字前面有三
And eight of them have a three before it.
像是刻意安排的
That's too many times to be random.
这是个密码
lt's a code.
还有什么？
What else?
没了
Nothing.
特别的地方是三和七
So, it's the three and the seven that are interesting.
因为像刻意安排的
Because they happen too many times to be random.
那是因为数字代表文字
Because they're not numbers, they're words.
像是往左或往右
Right-left, or left-right.
老套了
Old school,
是保险箱密码
a combination to a safe.
- 他们在饭店里？ - 是的
ln the hotel?
哪一家？ 我们查到的就是这间
Where? That's as close as l can track.
怎么样？
What do you have for me?
我们现在在找一个男的 他和一个女孩在一起
We're looking for a man now, who is supposed to be with the girl...
他有武器，非常危险
He's armed and to be considered extremely dangerous.
警察局的人说他是…
Dispatch says he's ...
身高大约五帐一 褐色头发、三十多岁…
About five, eleven, brown hair, thirties...
大约几小时前入住的
Ah, probably came in here less than a few hours ago.
我们无法透露房客数据
Sir, we're not allowed to discuss our guests.
他是房客吗？
So, he's a guest? Did he check in?
他有入住吗？ 先生，我们无法…
l'm sorry, sir. We're not at liberty to...
他带着十一岁的中国女孩
He would be with a Chinese girl, eleven years old.
我是她爸爸 我很担心我女儿
l'm her father. And l'm very worried about her.
很抱歉，我可以帮你报警
l'm so sorry. l can call the police for you.
敢我就轰了的头
Do that and l blow your brains out.
他住几号房？
Now, what room is he in?
What room is he in?
好像是十楼的房间
l think maybe, l put him on the tenth floor.
房号!
Room!
他身边真的没有小女孩
l swear he didn't have a little girl with him.
房号
Room.
- 我查一下 - 那就快点
l just need to check. Then check quick.
不然就把干掉
Before l put a bullet in your brain.
快点! 把手举起来
Quick! Put your hands up.
劝你别来惹我!
You don't want any part of this!
把手举起来
Hands up so l can see them.
通通不准出去!
No one leaves the hotel!
进来!
Come on!
是1012房
Ten, twelve. He's in room ten, twelve.
你还说坏蛋不会来
l thought you said no one would look for us here.
关掉了，是我关的
lt's off. l turned it off. So no one could call.
这样才不会有人打来 关掉也找得到
lt doesn't need to be on.
回来!
Get back!
通通趴在地上!
Get down on the floor!
不准出去!
Everybody get back!
把号码写下来 前面有三和七的就好 快点
Write down the numbers. Just the ones with the three and seven in front of them. Quick.
给我过去!
You get over there!
坐好!
Get up!
我会找地方安置
l'll try to get you someplace safe.
假如我们走散了 别说有给过我密码
lf we get separated, don't tell them you told me anything. Lie.
编个谎话
lf they try to scare you...
如果他们吓唬 吓我？我已经够怕了
Try? l'm so scared already.
是啊，我也是 记住，编个谎话
Yeah, me too. Remember, lie.
我们快到了
We're almost there.
如果他们俩在楼下 别杀那个女孩
lf you see them downstairs try not to kill the girl.
进去
Get back inside.
快追他们! 我去楼下拦截
Follow them! l'm going back down to cut them off.
条子来了
The cops are here.
拖住他们，等我的指示
Hold them off until l give the word.
别让他们进来!
Do not let them in!
全部蹲下!
Everybody stay down!
通通别想跑!
You ain't going nowhere! Stay!
全部不准动!
Everybody's going to sit down!
- 快追!别跑!蹲下! - 走开!
Go! Get back! Get down!
快追!
Go!
看着她 看着她
起来，全部起来
Get up! Everybody up.
掩护我们离开这里
We're getting out of the hotel.
快起来!
Up!
否则我开始杀人 起来!
Or l start killing you. Up!
嫌犯在58街转角
At the corner of 58th, we got a suspect.
站住!
Hey! Don't move.
Don't move.
到街上去!继续走!
lnto the street! Keep moving!
不听话就会跟他一样
Anyone who doesn't dies like this.
到街上去!
lnto the street!
快点!
Go!
停火!
Hold your fire!
嫌犯在人群中无法辨识
Suspects in the crowd. We can't lD them.
给我站住!
Hey! Stop right there!
开车…!
你要干嘛？
Hey! Hey! What the Hell are you doing?
那是我的车!
That's my car!
警察，他抢了我的车!
Look! That guy took my fucking car!
到市区，我再跟你讲地址
Head downtown, l'll give you an address in a minute.
他妈的!
Shit!
老兄，有地址吗？
Hey Buddy, you want to give me an address? Piotor lvanovov Hey Buddy, you want to give me an address?
（皮托依凡诺夫）
Piotor lvanovov ln a minute, just hold on.
等我一下 等我一下
ln a minute, just hold on.
（正在拨打给瓦西里）
你是谁？ 这还用问？ 当然是皮托
Who's this? Who do you think? lt's Piotor.
你没我的号码吗？
Don't you have me in your phone?
皮托？ 条子说你挂在地铁里…
Piotor? Police reports said you were found on the subway, with...
条子在唬烂
Police reports were wrong.
其它人都…
The others got...
什么声音？
What's that?
抱歉，讯号不良
Sorry, bad connection.
我问到密码了
l have the number.
你说什么？ 小孩被带走前 我们已经问到号码了
You what? Before the guy grabbed her, we got the number from her...
这段时间我都在躲条子
l've been ducking the cops for hours.
伊果，记下这个号码
lgor, put this number into your phone.
快把密码跟我说
Go ahead, give it to me.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
号码有一大长串
lt's on a piece of paper a kilometer long.
你人在哪？
Where are you?
小心他引条子来
He might be bringing the cops.
要赶走客人吗？
Should we clear the place out?
如果有条子来 混在人群中比较安全
lf there are cops we're better off in a crowd.
而且这里是自己的地盘
Still, we need better positions.
好吧，皮托…
Alright Piotor...
该轮你出风头了
now's your chance to be a hero.
到玛摩奇卡餐厅
Mamoschka's .
快点来
Be here soon.
马上到
l'll be there.
他回来了
He's here,
路克莱特回来了
Luke Wright, back in the city.
在我的地盘里 他回来一阵子了
ln my city. Actually, he's been back for a while.
一阵子？那是多久？
A while? What's a while?
一年吧，很难讲
Maybe a year, it's hard to say.
给我关掉
Turn that god damned thing off.
艾力克斯
Alex.
怎么回事，沃夫？
What's going on Wolf?
为何会扯上路克？
And how is Luke Wright involved in it?
我也正想问你
l figured l might ask you the same question.
别耍嘴皮子
Don't try to game me.
你根本不是个咖
You're not even a pawn,
想飞黄腾达又没本事
playing on a board so big you can't even see the edge.
你就是这块料
That's all you've ever been.
我很了解路克
l know about Luke Wright.
但他现在让我捉摸不透
Which is more than you can say until five minutes ago.
你对他的了解
What you know about Luke Wright rates less than a paragraph
对我们一点屁用都没有
in a very fat book.
世贸大楼倒塌之后
After the towers fell,
所有人力都用来找恐怖份子
and our manpower was spread out tracking terrorist activity...
是我组织了项目组
l was the one who formed the special
处理那段时间的所有罪案
task force to deal with the crime that was filling the gap.
请你别忘了 是我让你带队的
And don't you ever fucking forget that l was the one who put you in charge.
我没忘掉 你是靠我才当上市长的
l didn't forget, my work made you Mayor.
靠你？
Your work.
你以为路克是一般警察吗？
You think Luke was just one of your cops?
当我在组队时 我知道我需要个高手
When l put together your team, l knew l needed an edge.
一个能力超越一般探员
No ordinary detectives could give me.
身手不凡的人
l needed something surgical.
我请匿迹江湖的老友们推荐
l called friends in places buried so deep they don't officially exist.
他们都很帮忙
They were sympathetic.
一周后路克就出现了
A week later they sent Luke Wright.
这七年来消失的老大们
Those Wise Guys who vanished over the last seven years.
你以为是自相残杀的结果吗？
You think that was internecine war?
死在水沟里的大毒枭…
Those Coke Kings you found in the gutter in Harlem...
布鲁克林的弗莱迪佩卓 中国城的刘汤米
Freddy Petrovich in Brooklyn, Tommy Lau in Chinatown.
路克莱特是个鬼魂
Luke Wright is a ghost.
专门索命的猛鬼
A very deadly ghost.
他的本事还真不小
And it worked like a charm, too.
一切都怪你们这些蠢蛋贪污
Then you dicks had to get greedy and pad your pockets.
路克是个杀手 但他为人正直
Luke's a killer, but he's an honest one.
他当时想向内务组投诉
When he threatened to take the whole thing to lA...
是很多高层劝他才罢休的
...it took some people with a lot of bronze stuffed in their pajamas to talk him off the ledge.
对，后来专案组被解散 我们又成了打杂的
Yeah, and my team gets dismantled and we're peons again.
如果路克关系这么好
But if Luke Wright's so connected,
何必沦落到纽泽西打黑市拳击？
how's he wind up in Jersey cage fighting in the B circuit?
我是心理医生吗？
Do l look like a shrink?
叫所有人来
Get everybody on this.
一旦路克莱特出手
Once Luke Wright gets on a roll
全市只有一个人能跟他匹敌
there's only on man in this city can take him on one on one.
打扰了，我知道你们在开会
Excuse me. l know this this is a closed door.
但有间饭店发生大枪战
But there was just a major gun battle downtown at a hotel.
媒体都在报，你得出面发言
The media is going nuts. You're going to need to make a statement.
韩交也回来了
Han Jiao is in the city, also.
有个中国女孩有他的东西
He gave this little Chinese girl something.
我不知道是什么
l don't know what.
女孩被路克带走了
-Luke Wright grabbed her before l could. - What?
什么？ 我是说路克… 听到了…
- l said Luke Wright... - Yeah, yeah...
你刚才说过了
l heard you the first time.
封锁曼哈顿的所有对外道路
Close every exit out of Manhattan.
不准让路克或是女孩逃走 你就有好处可拿
Make sure the neither Wright or the girl gets away; you get commission.
要是人跑了 你就准备帮自己收尸吧
Let 'em go; you got a shovel to dig your own grave.
不准让那个女孩踏出纽约一步
That girl does not leave this city.
是谁杀了那个俄国人？
Who was this man who killed the Russians?
我不知道 他没有告诉我
l don't know. He didn't tell me.
他有没有问到那个数字？
Did he ask you about the number?
每个人都问这个数字
Everyone asked me about the number.
那跟他们讲些什么呢？
And what did you tell them?
我什么都没说
Nothing.
什么？
What?
我什么都没说
Nothing.
在撒谎!
You are lying!
韩叔叔，我不会对你撒谎的
l would never lie to you, Uncle Han.
打个电话告诉他们
Call our men back home.
把阿梅的妈妈干掉
Tell them to kill Mei's mother,
因为她的女儿是骗子
because her daughter is a deceitful liar.
韩叔叔，我发誓
l swear, Uncle Han.
我假装不会说英文，也听不懂
l pretended l didn't speak English, or understand it.
他们又吼又叫的 但是我什么都没说
They screamed and shouted but l didn't say anything,
因为我知道你会生气的
because l knew it would upset you.
我向我妈发誓
l swear on my mother.
找到女孩了
We recovered the girl.
但数据可能泄漏了
But the information might have been compromised.
要改时间吗？
Should we change our time frame?
不可能 事情已经闹得沸沸扬扬了
lmpossible, now that the whole damn thing has gone super nova.
想交易就订今晚
lf it's going to happen, it's going to happen tonight.
会面地点必须更改
The meeting place needs to be changed.
改到哪里？
Where to?
我会再通知你 到了，就是这里
l'll let you know. Here. Right here.
慢一点
Slow down.
停车
Stop the car.
不行 妓女不准上我的车
No. You don't bring no hookers in my cab, man.
表照跳就是了
Just keep the meter running.
美女…
Ladies...
去喝一杯吧
How about a drink.
晚安
Good evening.
晚安 请问有订位吗？
Good evening. Will you be joining a reservation?
我们没订位
No, we don't have a reservation.
晚点会客满
lt will be later tonight,
不过现在应该有位子 不介意的话可以坐楼上
but we should be able to find you something.
You can sit upstairs, if you like.
先生，你的意思呢？
Sir, do you have a preference?
去酒吧喝杯酒就好了
l think we'll just get a drink at the bar.
先亲我一下 然后转身离开这里
Why don't you give me a kiss, turn around and walk out of here.
我以为…
But l thought...
假装掉了东西在外面
Just act like you forgot something outside.
千万别再进来
Only, don't come back.
一杯白俄罗斯，谢谢 还有一支叉子
Give me a White Russian please, and a fork.
叉子？
A fork?
对，就是那个
Yeah, one of those.
每到这种时刻我都会辞穷
l never know what to say in these moments.
什么时刻？
What moments?
我准备杀人的时刻
The ones before l kill somebody.
老大!
Boss!
他开什么车？ 车停哪里？
What does he drive? And where is it parked?
休旅车，停在外面的巷子
lt's an SUV in the alley outside.
瓦西里
Vassily.
猜错了
Not even close.
你是谁？ 今晚不断杀你手下的人
Who is this? The guy who's been killing your boys all night, Emile.
也是抓走你儿子的人
The guy who has your son tied up in a very dark place.
这是我的条件… 你以为我会鸟你吗？
Now, here's what l want. Do you think l give a shit what you want?
你以为抓了他就能威胁我吗？
Do you think you can blackmail me, because you have Vassily?
他死了你就下地狱!
Kill him and go to Hell!
我是会下地狱
Oh, l'm going to Hell alright.
我不会杀你儿子
l'm not going to kill your boy.
我会把他留在身边 当作宠物
l'm going to keep him around. Like a pet.
被主人虐待的宠物
A very badly treated pet.
我会做出令人不齿的事
l'm going to do things to him that will make me ashamed to look in the mirror afterward.
但我还是会做
But l will do them.
瓦西里会供出你组织的秘密
Vassily's going to tell me everything he knows about your operation.
然后你会怎样？ 报警吗？
And then what you going to do? Tell the police?
你想逗我笑吗？ 谁说要报警了？
You want me to laugh? Who said anything about the police?
我要爆料给你的对手
l'm going to share the information with the competition.
那些还活着的对手
The one's l haven't already killed.
他们没杀死的人就让我来动手
Anything they don't take from you, l will.
首先是你老婆
First, l'm going to take your trophy wife.
再来是你的孩子们
Then l'm going to take trophy children.
最后你会一无所有
Then l'll leave you with nothing.
最后你会没人替你送终
When l'm done, you won't even be a memory of a memory.
你可以避免这一切
But that doesn't have to happen.
你要什么？
What do you want?
保险箱里装了什么？
l want to know what is in the safe?
哪个保险箱？ 那女孩告诉我密码了 就是那一个
What safe? The safe the girl gave me the combination too. That safe.
三千万美金
Thirty million dollars.
那女孩要去拿第二组号码
The kid was on her way to get a second number.
第二个保险箱装了什么？
What is in the second safe?
不值三千万的东西
Something worth thirty million dollars.
谁的东西？
To who?
不知道
No idea.
因为你不够聪明，艾米尔
That is because you are only half smart, Emile.
那就这么办
So, here's the deal.
说出第一个保险箱在哪 我拿到钱就放人
You tell me where the first safe is. l take the money and let your boy go.
敢骗我你就完了
Lie to me, and your world ends. You have my word on that.
我说到做到 白痴
ldiot.
我知道你只有一个人 一个人是办不到的
l know when a man is working alone. And you're as alone as one can be.
你需要军队才能靠近那个保险箱
You need a small army to get near that safe.
我有军队
The kind of army l have.
那是过去式了
Had.
军队刚才缩编了
lt's been shrinking by the minute.
再不说你儿子就要倒霉了
Last chance before l hang up and go to work on your son.
你要杀我吗，收垃圾的？
You going to kill me, garbage man?
你那天大可杀了我们的
You could have taken us out that day, couldn't you?
但你却坐在地上
But you just sat there. Let us ruin you.
任凭我们宰割
Let us make you nothing.
保险箱似乎给了你新希望 对吧，收垃圾的？
l guess finding out about that safe gave you new motivation, Garbage man?
换作我才不会聊天
l wouldn't spend my time talking if l were you.
我会祷告
l'd spend it praying, when this is over,
希望小女孩别因此丧命
that little girl is still alive.
祷告吧
Pray.
时间和地点？ 一小时后在桥下的通道
When and where? The underpass, under the bridge, one hour.
被老俄袭击时…
l'm sorry l pointed a gun at you,
很抱歉用枪指着
when the Russians attacked us, Mei.
- 当时我… - 我知道是生意
lt was... Business. l know.
很好，了解就好
That's good. lt's good you understand.
我们会完成这件事
We're going to get this done.
我和韩叔会照顾的
And you'll be safe with me and uncle Han
我保证会当个好爸爸 绝不会抛弃你们母女
l promise to be a better father to you than the one who left you and your mother.
最关心的人只有我
There's no one in the world who cares more about you.
最清楚了，对不对？
You know that, don't you?
队友都到齐了
Well, the gang's all here.
还差一位
Almost.
莱迪克请病假吗？
Reddick have to call in sick?
他还在医院，混帐! 他的气管被你打断了
He's in the hospital, dickhead! You broke his trachea.
原来气管会断喔
l didn't know a trachea could brake. l hope they can fix it.
希望医生能处理 我来处理你好了
Yeah, how 'bout l fix you.
别在这动手
Hey, hey, hey... Not here.
好久不见，路克
Been a while, Luke.
真不想看到你
Can't say l missed you.
还是言归正转吧
So, let us get down to business.
我要的东西有带吗？
Did you bring what l asked for?
是史考提的吗？
Scotty's ?
不然呢？
Where else?
真好吃
That's good.
我在餐厅耗了整晚
l've been in restaurants all night.
里面只有供应子弹
All l got served was lead.
有打火机吗？
Anyone got a light?
我告诉你，去你的!
You know what? Screw this!
听我说，队长 你一讲我们就来了
Look, Cap, You asked us to come here. So we came.
但我才不要听他的废话
But l ain't going to sit here and listen to this scumbag's big mouth.
闭嘴，柯费斯
Shut up Kolfax.
还没戒啊？
Still haven't quit, huh?
那是什么？
Hey, what the hell is that? Combination to the safe with thirty million bucks in it.
装了三千万的保险箱的密码 奸诈的人渣
Whoa, whoa, What the hell you filthy piece of shit.
现在只有我知道密码
The only place it exists now is in here.
下次千万别乱开枪
Remember that next time your little trigger finger gets itchy.
这里是中国城最夯的赌场
Why would Han Jiao stash it right in the middle of Chinatown's
韩交为何把钱放在这？
busiest gambling den?
因为像你这种条子
Because of sleazbucket cops.
最爱来这种地方收钱
Like you Benoit, who collect off of Chinatown's busiest gambling den.
否则这么多保镳拿枪
Where else would he be surrounded by dozens of armed men
条子怎么都不起疑？
without attracting police attention?
队长，搞不好他在骗人
Alight Captain, how do we know this son-of-abitch is on the level?
他是个无赖 你的消息哪来的？
Huh? He's a bum. Where'd you get your information?
今晚有个大交易
There's an exchange happening tonight.
中国帮一半的财产都在这
The Triad half of the deal is in the safe at the Casino.
我一个人搞不定 所以才找老搭档们一起来
No way l could get to it on my own. So l called on you, my old pals.
三千万分六份还是很多
Thirty million split six ways is still a lot of money.
风险很高，队长
We're risking a lot, Captain.
特别是你 大家都知道你前途无量
You especially. Everybody knows you have a bright future.
谁能保证？市长吗？
Promised by who? Hizzonor?
他在耍你，沃夫
What carrot is he teasing you with, Wolf?
他知道你的事哪敢用你
He's going to let off the street knowing what you know?
这话什么意思？ 代表他的第二任期快结束了
Hey, what's that supposed to mean? Meaning his second term is going to come to an end,
很快就没权力了
and his old on the city goes puff.
他会变成平民百姓
Just like that, he's Joe Citizen again.
三千万退休金还不错
Thirty million would be a nice retirement package.
他给了老中什么好处？
What's he giving the Chinks?
我要是知道 就不会找你们这群混蛋
lf l knew that, l wouldn't be standing here with you assholes, would l?
前途无量是吗？
Bright future, huh?
上头条新闻
Big headlines.
英勇警探破获纽约最大地下赌场
"Hero cops take down New York City's biggest underground gambling operation.
每人分五百万
Five million bucks apiece.
没有人会发现 打点一下就可以了
No one will ever know about it, just to give it that extra sweet taste.
好，有谁进去过？
Alright, who's been in there?
快说，谁进去过？
For Christ sake, who's been in there?
我，队长
Me Cap.
你们两个走前面
You two, you're on point.
里面都是平民 所以要见机行事
The place is packed with civilians. So exercise some judgement.
别忘了，密码在我这
Remember, l got the combination.
想要钱就保护我
You want that money? Watch my back.
你要去哪？
Hey, where you going?
别动!
Don't move!
不准抵抗!妈的!
Hey you! Settle down!
往这走!快点!
This way!
妈的!
Jesus!
警察…
Warn them!
警告他们!
莱斯基，小心点!
Lasky, heads up!
前进!
Go!
柯费斯，干掉他!
Kolfax, take him out!
掩护他!
Cover him!
快点打开!
Open it! Take it!
他妈的!好痛!
Oh fuck! Aww shit!
惨了…我得去医院
Aw shit. l got to get out of here.
好痛…队长…
Aww fuck. Aw Captain...
你这混蛋! 竟然从背后开枪!
God, you shit! Shoot a man in the back!
王八蛋!
Son of a bitch!
米尔斯，该往哪走？
Alright, Mears. Where're we going?
往这走
This way.
快点!
Move!
我们被袭击了
We've been attacked...
他们不是俄国人
Not by the Russians. Buy the police l think...
好像是警察 不过他们比警察更厉害
But they're better than police.
多派点人来 他们杀了很多人 快点，我们需要…
We need help. They've killed a lot of our people.
找小张 尽快拿到那个数字
Call Chang. Tell him as soon as he gets that number,
然后把跑腿的干掉
he is to take out their errand boy.
这个数字由我们自己来破解
We'll have to decipher the code quickly...
你们听到了吗？
Do as l said!
通往天堂之门 看来不是为罪人而开的
The Gates of Paradise. Locked and bolted to sinners like us.
那我们就自己开吧
Yeah, well let's not wait for an invitation.
好了，混蛋，你可以开工了
Alright you bastard. Get started.
先把规则讲好
Here's how we do this.
你们把枪放下
You put down your guns...
我就开保险箱
...l open the safe.
想杀我就杀吧
You want to shoot me, go ahead.
快点决定 正牌的条子快到了
Make your minds up quick, because the real cops will be here soon.
扔在地上
On the floor.
别开玩笑了
Come on you son of a bitch, what are you trying to pull.
你在耍什么花样？ 左右弄反了
l got right left switched.
会开的
lt's going to open.
他妈的!
Oh fuck!
你不会死的
You'll live.
往左转到26
Left, twenty six.
沃夫队长，发生什么事？
Captain Wolf, what the hell happened in here?
你说呢？
What do you think happened, huh?
我们突袭失败了
We had a raid on the place go bad.
里面有不少人伤亡
We got dead cops, casualties, get in there will ya!
快去帮忙!
Captain Wolf, you need an ambulance.
沃夫队长，你需要去医院 快派救护车队来
l need a fleet of ambulances! Alright?
快去通报 我自己会去医院
Call it in, will ya? l'll take my own busted ass to the hospital.
还不赖嘛
Not bad.
如果你没有那么虚假
lf you weren't such a double dealing asshole,
我还有可能会欣赏你
l could almost like you.
只是可能而已，开车吧
Almost. Drive.
擦伤而已
lt's a scratch.
我不会杀你
l'm not going to kill you.
但也没说要让你好过
But l didn't say l was putting you up in the Ritz.
沃夫
Wolf.
钱在我这，丹尼
l have your money, Danny.
什么？
What?
你听到了
You heard me.
三千万，面额是五千和一千
Thirty million, five thousand and one thousand dollar bills.
我想谈谈…
- l want to talk... - No. No,
不…你先冷静一下 我们好好的谈
what you want to do is calm down so we can talk like adults.
闭嘴，丹尼
Shut it, Danny.
我要谈条件
l want to talk. But l don't want to talk to you.
但我不想跟你谈 我要找你的男友谈
l want to talk to your boyfriend.
我是艾力克斯
This is Alex.
好久不见，艾力克斯
lt has been a while, Alex.
你哪来的号码？
How did you get this number?
别傻了，艾力克斯 抠抠市长的屁屁就有了
Come on, Alex. Reach up the Mayor's ass there you are.
该来的总是避不掉
A man has got to do, what a man has got to do.
他比安妮好多了
Well, he was a better catch than Annie was anyway.
我不懂你为何会看上她
l never understood how you hooked up with a cow like that.
这与长相无关 我喜欢她的幽默
lt was never about her looks. lt was her sense of humor.
她不再幽默了吧？
She is not so funny now, is she?
你说得对，我也是
No, she is not, neither am l.
钱在我这，艾力克斯
l have the money, Alex.
杀了不少人才得到的 所以给我听清楚
l had to kill a lot of people to get it, so listen up.
你还没交易密码
You haven't made the combination exchange yet.
另一个保险箱里装了什么？
What is in the other safe?
一张光盘
A disk.
记录名字和金流…
Names, money trails...
指挥官派你和我协助丹尼时
...when our commanders sent the two of us to help Danny clean up the city,
他们有附带条件
they attached a price.
丹尼必须不闻不问
ln exchange Danny looked the other way...
被判定为恐怖组织的帮派
...while the assets seized from every group deemed
其资产都归他们所有
a terrorist organization were funneled into their private accounts.
没想到为了保命
lt's amazing what people let you get away with
那些人什么都愿意给
when they are scared and want to feel protected.
没想到有这么多豺狼虎豹想分杯羹
Amazing how many scumbags there are out there waiting to take advantage of it.
你别自命清高了
- Like you didn't . - l quit.
我改变了
l bet that helps all those souls
那些无故被你干掉的人
you sent to meet their maker without due process,
终于可以安息了
rest a whole lot easier.
你以为参加黑市拳赛
You thought you could atone by climbing into a cage
故意挨揍就能弥补一切？
and allowing yourself to get beaten to a pulp.
少跟我说教了，路克
Don't fucking preach at me, Luke.
我只是拿钱办事
l'm getting paid for services rendered.
对 你把光盘卖给老中 让他们勒索高层
Right. You sell the disk to the Chinese so they can black mail our old honchos.
拿着那三千万 带着丹尼去巴哈马享乐
Take the thirty mil and waltz off with Danny to a Villa in the Bahamas.
Q里岛也不错
Bali, but whatever, eh?
你都知道了 那接下来呢？
So, now you know. Now what?
你现在得跟我交易了
Now you're dealing with me.
好，那我不找他们了
Alright, l'm turning around.
不行
No you're not.
什么意思？
What are you talking about?
钱在你手上 中国帮对我没用处
You got the money, the Chinese have nothing l care about.
不，他们有我想要的东西
No, they have something l do.
记住，当他给梅密码，就动手
把保险箱密码给她
Give her the combination to your safe.
她会给你我们的 我们各自到对方的地方
And she will give you our number. We go to your location, you go to ours.
等我们拿到光盘 我们会教你解a
When we've gotten the disk, we will explain the code.
你就能拿到钱了
And you get the cash.
一言为定
That's the deal.
快讲吧
Let's hear it.
密码很长，你最好写下来
lt's a very long number. You'll want to write it down.
还好我有带笔
Thank goodness l brought a pen. Huh?
最好闭上眼睛
You might want to close your eyes.
随便
Have it your way.
快接电话…路克
Come on, Luke.
你我到老地方见
The old place. Just you and me.
你是路克的朋友？
You're a friend of Luke's ?
不能算是
Not as far as you're concerned.
今晚发生的枪战事件
The violence that has rocked the city tonight continued in a bloody gun battle...
大约在一个小时前 已转战中国城的夜总会
...in a Chinatown night club, less than an hour ago.
这件事很棘手
This is really getting out of hand.
是吗？多谢你的观察
You think? Thanks for that insight.
市长，艾力克斯罗森在专线
Your Honor. Alex Rosen is on your private line.
他说有急事
He says that it's urgent.
不好意思，市长… 五分钟后再说 现在别烦我
Excuse me, your Honor... Back in five, don't bother me now.
他为何不打手机？
Why didn't he call me on my cell phone?
我说过通通转接到手机…
l thought l told you to put all my calls through to the Cell phone.
我常说这里的保全很烂
l always told you this place had lousy security standards.
那是因为没人敢来撒野
Well, that's because noboby's been crazy enough to come in here and pull a stunt like this.
你真带种，路克
You got some balls, Luke.
我不仅带种，还很杀
Yeah, amazing l can even walk.
光盘拿来
The disk.
你以为我会笨到…
What, you think l'm stupid enough to let a gang of Chinese
让中国帮随便就能得手？
walk up the front steps and collect it from me in my living room?
光盘在远处的保险箱里
lt's in a safe, far away from here.
我不认为你是个笨蛋
l don't think you're stupid.
所以我才认为你有备份
Which is why l don't for a second you gave away the only copy.
我会跟艾力克斯碰面
l'm going to meet Alex.
你得先给我光盘
First you're going to give me the disk.
否则我会避开要害
Or l'll put bullets in places that won't kill you.
让你这辈子生不如死
But it will make you spend the rest of your life wishing l had.
满意了吗？
Satisfied?
放进计算机让我检查
l want to make sure it's not "ABBA's Greatest Hits" .
艾力克斯会杀了你的
Alex will kill you, you know?
或许吧
Yeah, probably.
天啊 路克，你的气色真差
Jesus Luke, you look like Hell.
只是酗酒
Just alcohol,
没晒太阳和缺乏睡眠
lack of sunlight, sleep deprivation...
其它的还不错
...other than that l feel great.
我有一次在想…
You know, l was thinking.
我们扔了多少尸体在这？
How many bodies did we dump in this place?
我从来不算的
You know, l didn't keep count.
不过全都是坏蛋，对吧？
They were all assholes though. Right?
放了她，艾力克斯
Let her go, Alex.
丹尼打来
Danny called,
说你找过他
told me about your visit.
不得不佩服你 连我也料想不到这招
l have to admit, even l didn't see that one coming.
你有了光盘和钱
You have the disk and the money.
她算得了什么？
What is she to you?
生命
Life.
那就及时行乐吧
Well, enjoy it while it lasts.
因为她会害你短命的
Because she is the reason yours is going to be a whole lot shorter.
钱拿来，路克
Money, Luke.
在车上
The Car.
也可能在银行
Or in a bank.
也可能在车站的置物柜
Or in a series of lockers in Grand Central.
也可能捐去做慈善了
Or maybe l donated it to charity.
我可是善心人士
Out of the goodness of my heart.
如果你想要钱
lf you want to find out where that money is,
就凭真本事拿吧
you are going to have to do it the hard way.
没事吧？
Are you alright Mei?
我看过他打架
l saw him fight before.
要赢他很难
Bad business for you.
对，非常难
Yeah, the worst.
又救了我一命
You saved me. Again.
我们救了彼此
We save each other.
我懂你的感受
l know how you feel.
帮我一起搬垃圾吧
Help me get this sack of garbage out of the car.
让他安然无恙的回家
Make sure he gets to his daddy safe and sound.
给你五万
Fifty grand.
算是补偿
For your trouble.
我知道钱不多 但你起码还有命享受
l know it don't seem like much. But at least you're going to live to enjoy it.
你希望他安然无恙吗？
You want him safe and sound?
他那样对你
After what he did to you?
那是为了她好
For her sake.
后会有期，我们互不相欠了
We meet again, all bets are off.
最尊敬的叔叔
Most revered Uncle.
这里有两千九百零九十五万美元
Here is twenty nine million, nine hundred and fifty thousand dollars.
我们会还剩余的五万 再加百分之十的利息
We will pay back the remaining fifty thousand, with interest.
如果万一您还生气
But in case you are still angry,
我必须告诉您
l must tell you this;
我知道您在中国城生意的每个账号
l know every account of every operation you have in Chinatown...
还有汇钱到中国的途径
and the money routes back to China.
您不找我们的麻烦 我们也不会找您的麻烦
You don't come after us, we won't come after you.
来追我们的话 你的世界就完了
Come after us... and your world ends.
我保证说话算话
You have my word on that.
给我准备飞机票
Get me on a flight home.
我再也不想看到这个…
lf l never set foot in this damned city again...
鬼地方!
lt will be too soon.
走路小心一点!
Watch where you are fucking going man!
走你的路去
Keep walking, pal.
借过？对不起？
Excuse me? Pardon me? Anything?
你是哑巴吗？ 这是他妈的纽约!
This is fucking New York City!
这是第五家银行 还有几家？
Bank number five. How many more?
没了
That's it.
每间银行的保险箱都有备份
There are copies of the disk in security boxes all over the city.
我们只要出事
Anything happens to us
就会有很多大人物倒霉
a lot of important people are going to be very sorry.
这是护身符
Our security.
是笔划算的生意
Good business for us.
现在要干嘛？
What now?
离开这个城市
Now we get out of town.
梅，年纪还小
Mei, you're a kid and...
我可能当不了好父亲
l'm not sure l could be a good father.
我不适合再当父亲了
l think that ship has sailed.
我不要父亲
l don't want no more fathers.
你愿意当我的朋友吗？
Will you be my friend?
当然愿意
Until my dying day.
西雅图有一所特殊学校
l've got info on a school for gifted kids up in Seattle.
那里很漂亮
lt's a nice drive,
希望喜欢风景
if you like trees and shit.
我们安全吗？
Are we safe?
过一天是一天，梅
One day at a time, Mei.
过一天是一天
One day at a time.